shopsafe.com.au 2017-12-14

# ShopSafe Privacy Policy

**The ShopSafe Privacy Policy Statement**

ShopSafe is ShopSafe Pty. Ltd. trading as The ShopSafe Trust.

ShopSafe is committed to protecting your privacy and the privacy of any personal information provided to us. ShopSafe complies with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the National Privacy Principles.

**What Anonymous Information do you or other third party advertisers collect?**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our websites. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here for NAI information](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

**Google and the[DoubleClick DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx):**

1\. Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site (and all ShopSafe sites).  
2\. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.  
3\. Users may opt out of the use of the [DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)  
4\. This site uses a tool which collects your requests for pages and passes elements of them to search engines to assist them in indexing this site. We control the configuration of the tool and are responsible for any information sent to the search engines 

**What personal information do you collect?**

To enable us to provide our services to you, we need to collect personal information from you – usually your name and email address. You may also choose to tell us your preferences and country of origin when searching ShopSafe web sites. You may also choose to provide us with your mobile phone number.

**How do you collect the personal information?**

We collect the information in a variety of ways - in person, in writing, by telephone, through our website and by other electronic communication channels. We may collect personal information about you from others when you choose to subscribe to our newsletter via an affiliated web site.

**Why do you need to collect this information and what do you do with it?**

****  
We collect your personal information to be able to send you the type of information that you have indicated you prefer. We may send this information by email or by SMS if you have indicated your preference for this.

Each time we use personal information for these purposes, we will give you the opportunity to decline to receive any further communications from us.

**What if I do not want to provide personal information.**

You are not obliged to provide us with your personal information but we cannot send you an email or sms message if you do not tell us where to send it.

**To whom do you disclose my personal information?**

We do not disclose your personal information to others.

We do not release your personal information to direct marketers or other websites.

We do not usually disclose your information to any other person for any other purpose unless we are authorised or directed by law to do so or unless you authorise its release.

We may be required by law or by an order of a court or tribunal to disclose your personal information to others. The Privacy Act also allows us to disclose personal information about you for purposes relating to public safety and law enforcement.

**Who will see or have access to my personal information?**

Apart from situations permitted by the National Privacy Principles, your personal information will only be seen or used: by persons working in or for ShopSafe; or organisations who may send emails or sms messages on our behalf. (We only disclose to these organisations the information they need to carry out the service and we undertake to seek their undertaking to maintain confidentiality of your information).

**Is my personal information secure?**

Our electronic information systems are password protected to prevent unauthorised access. Our staff are trained and required to protect the privacy of your personal information.

All service providers will be informed of the importance we place on protecting your privacy and their role in helping us to do this and we will ask them to undertake to maintain the confidentiality of your personal information. Any use of your personal information by them will be subject to the Privacy Act and the Principles.

**How long does ShopSafe keep my personal information and what do you do with it when I unsubscribe?**

**  
** We keep your information only for as long as you wish to continue receiving information from us.

Each time we use personal information for these purposes, we will give you the opportunity to decline to receive any further communications from us.

If you take this opportunity your personal information will be removed from all information stores maintained by us.

Our electronic records are maintained in password protected archives.

They are maintained so we can send you details of promotions or services, in which you may be interested. However, each time we send you something you have the opportunity to request that no further information be sent to you. Your personal information will then be deleted from our records.

**What if I want to check what personal information you hold about me?**

Subject to any restrictions in the Privacy Act or Principles, we will tell you on request what personal information we hold about you.

There will not be any charge to you where the information you request can be provided electronically.

There may be some cost involved in providing written records if the request is complex or requires detailed searching of our records.

**How can I correct my information?**

Every communication you recieve from us will include a link to enable you to update your preferences.

**What if I want further information or have a complaint or concern about the privacy protection of my personal information by ShopSafe?**

If you would like further information on our privacy policy or if you have any concerns over the privacy protection of the information you have given to us or that we have collected from others, please e-mail us at [privacy@shopsafe.com.au](mailto:privacy@shopsafe.com.au) or contact our office on 0755 999 999.
